A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, International Division, Asia and the Pacific, Manila Field Office Files FA642
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, International Division, Asia and the Pacific, Manila Field Office Files
1958-1984
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA642
32.4 Cubic Feet
27 boxes. Boxes 10 and 13 are legal size document boxes.
Separated Materials
Appendix A: Reports – Unpublished reports written by Ford Foundation staff and consultants were removed from their original folders, scanned and transferred to the Archives' collection of staff and consultant reports. See Appendix A for a list of these reports and their specific assigned number. The reports are listed in alphabetical order by author. The assigned number may be used to access reports in the online catalog.
Conditions Governing Access note
Material is open for scholarly research, with prior archival review.
Material more than ten years old is open for scholarly research.
Select individual files are restricted, as noted. Permission to access these files must be obtained from the Ford Foundation before scholarly access is permitted.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be restricted from scholarly research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment. Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.
Ford Foundation
- Subject Files, May 1987 Accession, 1958-1984; I
  - Agricultural Development Council (A/D/C), 1963-1981 (Box 1)
  - Agriculture (2), 1978-1981 (Box 1)
  - Arms Control, 1979-1981 (Box 1)
  - Arts (2), 1973-1981 (Box 1)
  - Asian Development Bank, 1966-1981 (Box 1)
  - Asian Institute of Technology, 1970-1980 (Box 1)
  - Association of Foundations -- Local Foundations, 1972-1977 (Box 1)
  - Business, Management and Industrial Development, 1973-1981 (Box 1)
  - Center for Research and Communications, 1975-1981 (Box 1)
  - China -- Memorandum Re: China Visit (Bell, Robinson, Bresnan, and Travers, September 1979), Sep 24, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Committee on the Management of Behavioral Studies in Population (COMBEP), 1975-1977 (Box 2)
  - Committee for Comparative Behavioral Studies in Population (740-0566), 1977 (Box 2)
  - Computer Use in Developing Countries, Data Analysis Seminars, 1970-1980 (Box 2)
  - Creative Writing in Southeast Asia -- Robert Shaplen, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Development Academy of the Philippines, 1974-1978 (Box 2)
  - Development Administration -- General, 1967-1979 (Box 2)
  - East-West Center, University of Hawaii, 1963-1981 (Box 2)
  - Economic Development Foundation, 1964-1977 (Box 2)
  - Employment in Less Developed Countries, 1970-1979 (Box 3)
  - Engineering and Technical Education -- Incl. Reports Re: Engineering in the Philippines, 1970-1978 (Box 3)
  - Fawcett, James -- Correspondence, 1974-1977 (Box 3)
  - Harvard University Public Service Fellowship Program, 1958-1981 (Box 3)
  - Indonesia -- General (2), 1975-1981 (Box 3)
  - Institute for International Education, 1968-1980 (Box 3)
  - International Council for Educational Development (ICED) -- "Operation Magdamayan", 1977-1978 (Box 3)
  - International Committee on the Management of Population Programmes (3), 1976-1980 (Box 4)
  - International Rice Research Institute (IRRI), 1964-1979 (Box 4)
  - International Union for the Scientific Study of Population (IUSSP), 1976-1977 (Box 4)
  - International Union for the Scientific Study of Population (IUSSP) -- General and Conference, Manila (December 1981), 1980-1981 (Box 4)
  - Japan, 1970-1981 (Box 4)
  - Korean Institute for Research in the Behavioral Sciences (KIRBS) and COMBEP, 1972-1981 (Box 4)
  - Language Teaching (3), 1970-1980 (Box 4)
  - Meetings -- International Division, Irrigation and Social Science Research, Representatives' Conferences, 1977-1980 (Box 5)
  - Meetings (2) -- Bangkok and New Delhi Meetings Re: Arts, Culture, Agriculture, 1980-1981 (Box 5)
  - Migration -- Ford Foundation and Rockefeller Foundation Research Program, 1979-1980 (Box 5)
  - Mindanao Development, 1964-1978 (Box 5)
  - Mindanao Development -- Incl. Reports Re: Ethnic Conflict, 1978-1980 (Box 5)
  - Mindanao Development -- Davao, 1973-1974 (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous (2), 1976-1979 (Box 6)
  - New International Economic Order, 1976-1980 (Box 6)
  - Nutrition, 1978-1982 (Box 6)
  - Pennsylvania State University -- Agricultural Economics, 1978-1979 (Box 6)
  - Philippine Council for Policy Science, 1976-1977 (Box 6)
  - Philippines, University of -- Economics in Demography, 1976-1977 (Box 6)
  - Philippines, University of (UP) -- General (folder 1), 1971-1981 (Box 6)
  - Philippines, University of (UP) -- General (folder 2), 1971-1981 (Box 6)
  - Population Center Foundation (PCF) -- Staff Development Program, 1975-1977 (Box 6)
  - Population Materials -- Reports, Proposals, 1978 (Box 7)
  - Population Meetings -- Joint Ford Foundation and Population Council, 1975-1976 (Box 7)
  - Population Office -- New York (2), 1975-1980 (Box 7)
  - Population Policy Research in the Social Sciences (Ford-Rockefeller) (4), 1976-1977 (Box 7)
  - Population Policy Research in the Social Sciences (Ford-Rockefeller) (5), 1977-1981 (Box 7)
  - Population Reports -- William Sweeney (2), 1974-1980 (Box 7)
  - Population Thailand -- General, 1976-1977 (Box 8)
  - Population and Management -- General, 1971-1976 (Box 8)
  - Program for the Introduction and Adaptation of Contraceptive Technology (PIACT), 1976-1979 (Box 8)
  - Refugees (2), 1979-1981 (Box 8)
  - Reports (Consultants) -- Pulled for Scanning (June 1987), n.d. (Box 8)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1963-1978 (Box 8)
  - Rural Development Thailand, 1973-1977 (Box 8)
  - Science Education, 1970-1976 (Box 9)
  - Social Sciences, 1970-1979 (Box 9)
  - Southeast Asian and Resources and Environment Conferences, 1977-1979 (Box 9)
  - Status of Women -- Reports Re: Women in Development, Education, Working Women, International Division's Women's Program Group, 1979-1980 (Box 9)
  - Status of Women -- Reports, Memoranda, Women's Program Group (5), 1980-1981 (Box 9)
  - Thailand (3), 1974-1980 (Box 9)
  - United Nations Development Programme (2), 1976-1984 (Box 10)
  - Value of Children (3), 1975-1978 (Box 10)
- Subject Files, 1969-1981; II
  - Inventory of I.E.C. Materials for the Philippine Population Program, 1969-1977 (Box 11)
  - Audio Cassette Technology, Oct 1973 (Box 11)
  - Ford Foundation Grants to Mindanao State University, May 1972 (Box 11)
  - Southeast Asia Fellowship Program -- Basic Grant Documents, 1971-1977 (Box 11)
  - Southeast Asian Studies Program, 1976-1981 (Box 11)
  - Southeast Asian Studies Program (2), 1970-1972 (Box 11)
  - Southeast Asian Studies Program (3), 1972-1975 (Box 11)
  - Population Reports -- William Sweeney, 1973-1976 (Box 11)
  - Status of Women, 1975-1977
  - Status of Women (3), 1977-1979 (Box 12)
  - Economic Education (3), 1976-1980 (Box 12)
  - Chiengmai -- Social Sciences, 1975 (Box 12)
  - Asian Productivity Organization, 1969-1971 (Box 12)
  - Agriculture (10), 1977-1978 (Box 12)
  - Community and Family Study Center, 1975-1976 (Box 12)
  - Southeast Asian Studies -- Fellowship Advisory Committee -- Kuala Lumpur, Nov 24-27, 1975 (Box 12)
  - Southeast Asian Fellowship Program -- General, 1975-1978 (Box 12)
  - Southeast Asian Fellowship Program (SEAFP) -- Advisory Committee Meeting, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia, Nov 26-27, 1975 (Box 12)
  - Southeast Asia Fellowship Program -- Grant Reports, 1976-1979 (Box 13)
  - Southeast Asia Studies (689-0872) -- Grant to the Faculty of Graduate Studies, Mahidol University, 1974-1976 (Box 13)
  - Southeast Asia Fellowship Program (SEAFP) -- Finance, 1974-1976 (Box 13)
  - Future Directions, 1975 (Box 13)
- Subject Files, 1978 Accession, 1960-1976; III
  - Abola Study, 1969 (Box 14)
  - Admissions Procedures and Admissions Testing Materials, 1969-1970 (Box 14)
  - Agricultural Modernization, 1969-1971 (Box 14)
  - Arts, 1968-1973 (Box 14)
  - Association of Colleges of Agriculture in the Philippines, Inc., 1963-1971 (Box 14)
  - Association of Southeast Asian Institutions of Higher Learning (ASAIHL), 1966 (Box 14)
  - Ateneo de Davao College -- Correspondence, 1961-1973 (Box 14)
  - Business, Economics, Management and Industrial Development -- General, 1964-1970 (Box 14)
  - Business, Economics, Management and Industrial Development -- General (2), 1970-1973 (Box 14)
  - Central Mindanao University, 1960-1974 (Box 15)
  - Central Philippine University, 1964-1972 (Box 15)
  - Computers, 1963-1969 (Box 15)
  - Overseas Development Conferences -- Agricultural Development -- Mexico City, Sep 1964 (Box 15)
  - Overseas Development Conferences, 1967-1970 (Box 15)
  - Conferences -- Asia-Pacific Education, Oct 1970 (Box 15)
  - Conferences (Local) -- Foundation, 1968-1972 (Box 15)
  - Conference -- Local Cooperative Relationships with U.S. Libraries, Nov 1970 (Box 15)
  - Cultural Center for the Philippines, 1967 (Box 15)
  - EROPA -- General, 1962-1976 (Box 15)
  - Economic Education, 1967-1971 (Box 15)
  - Foreign Area Fellowship Program, 1964-1974 (Box 16)
  - Foundation for Private Education in the Philippines, Inc., 1964-1967 (Box 16)
  - Foxfire, 1973 (Box 16)
  - Franklin Book Programs, Inc., 1963-1966 (Box 16)
  - Language Teaching -- General, 1964-1971 (Box 16)
  - Law Development -- General, 1962-1973 (Box 16)
  - Metropolitan Educational Television Association, 1963-1966 (Box 16)
  - Metropolitan Educational Television Association (META), 1965-1967 (Box 16)
  - National Science Development Board -- Institute of Food Technology, 1964-1967 (Box 16)
  - New York -- State University of New York (SUNY) Program, 1970-1975 (Box 16)
  - Pakistan Planning Project, 1964-1967 (Box 17)
  - Perkin, Gordon, 1968-1969 (Box 17)
  - Philippine Political Development (McHale Manuscript), 1964 (Box 17)
  - Philippines Rural Reconstruction Movement, 1961-1972 (Box 17)
  - Philippines -- General Information, 1961-1963 (Box 17)
  - Philippines -- Program Implementation Agency -- Planning and Programming Training Institute -- Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 17)
  - Population and Family Planning -- General (1), 1963-1968 (Box 17)
  - Population and Family Planning -- General (2), 1969-1970 (Box 17)
  - Population and Family Planning -- General (3), 1970-1971 (Box 17)
  - Population and Family Planning -- General (4), 1971 (Box 17)
  - Population and Family Planning -- General (5), 1971-1972 (Box 18)
  - Population and Family Planning -- General (6), 1971-1972 (Box 18)
  - Population and Family Planning -- Family Planning Organization of the Philippines, 1965-1969 (Box 18)
  - Regional -- Population -- Education (2), 1972-1974 (Box 18)
  - Supplement to Population Office Mailings, 1973-1974 (Box 18)
  - Population -- Survey Mission Report, Mar 1963 (Box 18)
  - Primate Research Center - International Institute for Study of Human Reproduction, 1963-1966 (Box 18)
  - Science Education -- General, 1961-1968 (Box 18)
  - Science Education -- General (2), 1968-1971 (Box 18)
  - SEAMES, 1965-1971 (Box 19)
  - SEAMES -- Agriculture (1), 1966-1975 (Box 19)
  - Southeast Asian Studies Program, 1967-1969 (Box 19)
  - Thailand, 1963-1970 (Box 19)
  - Training Programs (Economic Development and Others), 1962-1969 (Box 19)
  - United Nations Fund for Population Activities (UNFPA) -- Asia, 1972 (Box 19)
  - Vietnam, 1974-1975 (Box 19)
  - Wagner, Lew, 1969 (Box 19)
  - Wisconsin -- Workshop on University Administration, 1967-1971 (Box 19)
  - World Education, Inc. -- International Workshop for Program Evaluation Specialists, 1973-1974 (Box 19)
  - Wyzanski, Charles -- Visit, Jan 25-30, 1965 (Box 19)
- Subject Files, November 1981 Accession, 1963-1980; IV
  - Agratian Reform, 1963-1977 (Box 20)
  - Agriculture (9), 1974-1978 (Box 20)
  - Business Schools, 1972-1978 (Box 20)
  - Education (6), 1977 (Box 20)
  - Economic Education (2), 1971-1978 (Box 20)
  - International Committee on Management of Population Programs (ICOMP) (2), 1979 (Box 20)
  - Language Teaching, 1971-1977 (Box 21)
  - Ford Foundation Saigon, 1973-1974 (Box 21)
  - Philippine Population Review, 1972 (Box 21)
  - Population and Family Planning (12), 1974-1975 (Box 21)
  - Population and Family Planning (13), 1974-1978 (Box 21)
  - Population and Family Planning (14), 1974-1977 (Box 21)
  - Asian Association of Development Research and Training Institutes, 1973-1974 (Box 21)
  - Status of Women -- Materials, 1973-1975 (Box 22)
  - Social Science Research on Population and Development, 1974 (Box 22)
  - Population Office -- New York, 1973-1975 (Box 22)
  - Value of Children (1), 1971-1973 (Box 22)
  - Value of Children (2), 1974-1975 (Box 22)
  - Population and Family Planning -- General (7), 1971-1973 (Box 22)
  - Population and Family Planning (8), 1972-1973 (Box 22)
  - Population and Family Planning (9), 1973-1974 (Box 23)
  - Population and Family Planning (10), 1973-1974 (Box 23)
  - Population and Family Planning (11) [PHOTOS], 1974 (Box 23)
  - Philippine Educational Theater Association, 1971-1974 (Box 23)
  - Philippine-American Educational Foundation (2), 1970-1975 (Box 23)
  - Thailand (2), 1969-1974 (Box 24)
  - UST-PETA Project, 1972-1973 (Box 24)
  - Folklore (2), 1972-1974 (Box 24)
  - Education (4), 1969-1973 (Box 24)
  - Education (5), 1972-1976 (Box 24)
  - Population Program -- Philippines, 1972-1974 (Box 24)
  - PSSC Regional Workshop -- Enhancing the Roles of Social Science in Southeast Asia, 1976-1977 (Box 25)
  - SEASP Documents, 1976 (Box 25)
  - SEASP History of Southeast Project -- Philippine Project Team, 1977 (Box 25)
  - Mexico Conference, 1976 (Box 25)
  - Foreign Training Programs in Southeast Asia, 1976 (Box 25)
  - Population Policy Research in the Social Sciences (Ford Foundation/Rockefeller Foundation) (2), 1976-1980 (Box 25)
  - Population Policy Research in the Social Sciences (Ford Foundation/Rockefeller Foundation) (3), 1977-1978 (Box 25)
  - Japan, 1976-1977 (Box 25)
  - Economic Costs of Children, 1977 (Box 25)
  - Cali Conference, 1974 (Box 25)
  - Ateneo de Manila University, 1965-1976 (Box 25)
  - United Nations Development Programme, 1975-1976 (Box 26)
  - International Committee on Management of Population Programs (ICOMP), 1973-1977 (Box 26)
  - Workshop on University Administration, 1971-1977 (Box 26)
  - Xavier University, 1962-1971 (Box 26)
  - Value of Children Workshop, 1975-1976 (Box 26)
  - ESCAP -- Committee on Population -- IPS and SB Proposals, 1975-1980 (Box 26)
  - Population Commission, 1969-1975 (Box 27)
  - Self-Instruction in Population, 1976 (Box 27)
  - The Population Council, 1965-1975 (Box 27)
  - Population Policy Research in the Social Sciences (Ford Foundation/Rockefeller Program), 1970-1975 (Box 27)
  - Social Science Association of Thailand, 1975 (Box 27)
  - Program Planning -- Philippines, 1972-1975 (Box 27)
  - Program Planning and Budget Projection -- General, 1974-1975 (Box 27)
  - Volunteer Programs, 1966-1972 (Box 27)
  - Evaluation, 1968-1976 (Box 27)
  - Urban Development, 1971-1974 (Box 27)
  - Indonesia -- General (1), 1965-1975 (Box 27)
- Appendix A: Reports, 1973-1974
  - Colle, Royal D.; Audio Cassette Technology, Oct 1973 (Report #019869)
  - Wickham, Robert S.; Improving Family Planning Program Management in the Developing Countries, May 7, 1974 (Report #019921)